SAQIB MANZOOR

Present Mailing Address:

C-4, Street 2 Abdalian Society, near Punjab College, Johar Town R-Block Lahore, PAKISTAN

Cellular: +92-306-2454979

E-mail: saqib.bhat.sb@gmail.com

PROFILE:

To have a challenging position in chemical engineering where I could apply all major principles and my specialized interested areas of application namely thermodynamics, fluid dynamics by which I can apply my wide knowledge and professional expertise in the field of chemical engineering.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1. Name of the Organization: United Detergents, Lahore (3P of Unilever Pakistan)

Department: Production
Job Title: Shift Engineer

Period Served: From August 1st 2017 to Present

Job Responsibilities:

- Ensuring all production activities aimed at achieving good and consistent quality products, minimize customer complaints & non-conformances and quick response to fulfil planner demands.
- Maintain accident free environment through risk assessment, safety suggestions, near miss reporting and safety contacts.
- Minimize RM / PM wastage and cycle count variation.
- Monitoring of all shift wise entries into the SAP system on time and their onward release by QC and transferring to warehouse.
- Implement effectively all applicable ISO, GMP and other standards requirements in the respective production area.
- Troubleshooting quality and safety issues in a timely manner.
- Foreseeing potential problems before they happen via implementation of preventive maintenance plans.
- Safe operation and Investigating of Technical problems, analyze root causes and define solutions.
- Manage and utilize manpower effectively
- Ensuring SHE compliance at zone level.

2. Name of the Organization: Applus Velosi, Karachi, Pakistan

Job Title: Trainee Pipeline Engineer

Department: Velosi Asset Integrity Limited.

Period Served: From 23rd August 2016 to 31th July 2017

Job Responsibilities:

- Worked on Risk Based Inspection of <u>"TRANS ANATOLIAN NATURAL GAS PIPELINE PROJECT</u> (TANAP)"
- Identifying the damage mechanism & failure modes, assigning a probability of failure based on industry practice API 571.
- Reviewing and Verification of PFDs, P&IDs and Sectioning of the pipeline drawing.
- Assessing consequence of failure and creating the related inventory groups.



- Working and Review of Process data.
- Maintaining a filing system for all static equipment that contains information for the equipment tag number, location, and details of design and engineering data sheet, design drawings, materials, initial inspection data, and Mechanical assessment sheet.
- Uploading the spread sheet to the VAIL software for risk determination and calculation.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION			
Year	Degree	Specialization	Institute/University
2012-16	Bachelor	Chemical Engineering	Dawood University of Engineering and Technology, Karachi, Pakistan
2010-11	FSC	Pre-Engineering	Hamza Army Public School & College System, Rawalpindi, Pakistan
2008-09	Secondary	Science	Bismah Army Public School, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

SHORT COURSES & TRAININGS:

- ASPEN HYSYS (basic) From OMESOL (Octagon Management & Engineering Solutions). (Jan '15-july '15)
- MS OFFICE 2015(Word, Excel and PowerPoint). (Jan '16-Feb '16)
- AutoCAD (Basic) from Applus Velosi (Dec '16-Feb '17)
- One week training on "Liquid Penetrant and Magnetic Particle Testing".

REFERENCE:

Available on request.